The Parker Bailey Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Musical Works, Series X
  - Musical Works Composed by Parker Bailey, X.A
    - Vocal--Choral, X.A.3
      - Arise, O Church of God, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        1 score (1 sheet); 31 cm.
      - Autumn Carol (Box 5, Folder 6)
        See: Spring Carol
      - Autumn Soliloquy (TTBB), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        (Text by Charles Edward Parker)
        2 scores (8 pp.); 32 cm.
      - The Daisy (SSA), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        (Text by James Montgomery, abridged)
        1 score (9 pp.); 27 cm.
        Ink holograph; voices only
      - Evening Prayer (Box 5, Folder 6)
        See: A Vesper Prayer
      - Faith (TTBB), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 6)
        1 score (2 pp.); 27 cm.
        Copy with pencil markings
        Sketch on cover
      - Falstaff's Song (TTBB), 4 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        (Text by Edmund Clarence Stedman)
        1 score (3 pp.); 28 cm.
        2 scores (6 pp.); 35 cm.
        1 ink, 1 ink and pencil holograph
        Different keys
        (1) sketches (6 pp.)
      - Forrester's Song (TTBB), 6 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        (Text by Wm. Shakespeare)
        1 set of parts (2 sheets each); 27 cm.
        2 scores (6 pp.); 26 cm.
        Published by H.W. Gray, 1935
      - God is Everywhere, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 6)
        1 score (7 pp.); 27 cm.
      - God, Make Me Worthy of Today, 7 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        1 score (4 pp.); 27 cm.
        Photocopies
      - Gratias tibi Deo (2 part), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 6)
        1 score (2 sheets); 27 cm.
        Copy of holograph
      - How Gently Doth the Lord, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 6)
        1 score (1 sheet); 25 x 35 cm.
      - I Know a Little Rose (SA), 5 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        2 scores (4 pp.); 27 cm.
        Published by Oliver Ditson Co., 1935
      - I Know a Quiet Stream (TTBB), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 6)
        (Text by Charlton J.K. Hinman)
        1 score (5 pp.); 27 cm.
      - Let Christ Redeem Our World, 3 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text by Parker Bailey)
        2 scores (1 sheet); 27 by 32 cm.
        1 score (1 sheet); 32 cm.
      - The Lord's Prayer, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        2 scores (1 sheet); 26 cm.
        Published by C.R. Piety, 1950
      - The Lord Reigneth, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text--Psalm 93)
      - Manhattan (SSA), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text by Morris Abel Beer)
      - Memory (TTBB), 4 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        2 scores (5 pp.); 28 cm.
        Published Carl Fischer, 1935
        See also: Vocal Music composed by Parker Bailey for solo voice (X.A.2)--Memory
      - My Choice Bloom (SSA), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text adapted from Thomas Hood)
        1 score (4 pp.); 28 cm.
      - A Nation's Builders (SSAA), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text by Ralph Waldo Emerson)
      - Orpheus With His Lute (TTBB), 7 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Published H.W. Gray Co., 1935
        1 score (3 pp.); 31 cm.
        Chorus parts only
        2 scores (3 pp.); 32 cm.
        Copies of above
        Ink holograph; amplified piano part for use with full chorus
      - Resurrection, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text by Alice C. Jennings)
        1 score (1 sheet); 28 cm.
      - Robin (SSA), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text by G.C. Kattenhorn)
        1 score (5 pp.); 28 cm.
      - She is Not Fair (TTBB), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        2 scores (6 pp.); 28 cm.
        Published Oliver Ditson Co., 1931
      - Snow Dreams (SA and SSA), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Ink and pencil holograph; for SA
        Ink and pencil holograph; for SSA
      - Spring Carol (unison or two-part), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        With text and notes
      - Springtime, 4 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (text by G.C. Kattenhorn)
        2 scores (11 pp.); 28 cm.
        Published Oliver Ditson Co., 1934
        2 scores (8 pp.); 28 cm.
        Published Oliver Ditson Co., 1935
        SSA and optional bass
      - Summer is Singing (SS or SA), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        See also: Music composed by Parker Bailey for Solo Voice (X.A.2)--Summer is Singing
      - Summer Rain (SA), 5 items (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text by William Cox Bennett)
        [Version 1]
        [Version 2]
        [Version 3]
      - Summer Winds (SA), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text by George Darley)
      - To a Yellow Tulip (SA), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
        (Text by G.H. Kattenhorn)
        See also: Music composed by Parker Bailey for Solo Voice (X.A.2)--Four Songs for High Voice
      - To Helen (TTBB), 6 items (Box 5, Folder 8)
        (Text by Edgar Allan Poe)
        2 scores (4 pp.); 32 cm., 27 cm.
        Pencil holograph; tenor and piano setting
        (1) sketches (4 pp.)
      - To the Gentian (SSA), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 8)
        (Text by William Cullen Bryant)
      - The Touch Stone (ST), 3 items (Box 5, Folder 8)
        (Text by Samuel Bishop)
      - Under My Window (SSA), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 8)
        (Text by Thomas Westwood)
        Published by C.C. Birchard and Co., 1930
      - A Vesper Prayer, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 8)
        See also: Music composed by Parker Bailey for Solo Voice (X.A.2)--Evening Prayer
      - The Voice of Childhood (SSA), 3 items (Box 5, Folder 8)
        (Text by Laman Blanchard)
        Text (1 sheet-typescript) laid in.
        1 score (7 pp.); 32 cm.
        Ink holograph; voice parts only
        (1) Shetches (4 pp.)
      - When Morning Calls, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 8)
        [Text by C.R. Piety?]
        1 score (1 p.); 19 cm.
      - The Wind and the Moon (Treble Unison), 1 item (Box 5, Folder 8)
        (Text by George MacDonald)
        Ink holograph with typed notes
      - Worship the Spirit Everlasting, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 8)
        See also: Business Correspondence Related to Music (II.A)--Oxford University Press
  - Musical Works Arranged or Harmonized by Parker Bailey, X.B
    - Instrumental, X.B.1
      Arranged alphabetically by title of composition.
      - Setting of Newfoundland tune, Lord Thomas and Fair Elinor; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 1)
        1 poem
      - Notturno --arranged for two pianos, Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887; 5 items (Box 6, Folder 1)
        2 scores (15 pp.); 32 cm.
        1 score (14 pp.); 29 cm.
        1 score (14 pp.); 32 cm.
        (1) Sketches (7 pp.)
      - Sonata for Violin and Piano, op. 78 --arranged for flute and piano, Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 1)
        1 flute part (6 pp.); 32 cm.
        1 score (13 pp.); 32 cm.
        (1) Sketches (22 pp.)
      - Sonatina in C Major --arranged for two pianos, Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Sonatina in G Major --arranged for two pianos, Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Sonatina in F Major --arranged for two pianos, Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Sonatina in C Major --arranged for two pianos, Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 1)
        1 score (10 pp.); 35 cm.
        Vocal
    - Vocal, X.B.2
      Alphabetically by title.
      - The Call to Worship --harmonization, Piety, C.R.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        1 sketch (1 p.)
      - A Christmas Song --arranged for SA and piano, Parker, H.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text by Josiah Gilbert Holland)
      - Come, Sinner, Come --arranged for medium solo voice, Palmer, H.R.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text by V.E. Witter)
        Published H.W. Gray Co. Inc., 1939
      - Dates and Peaches --harmonization, Piety, C.R.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Farewell, Sweet Prairie --harmonization, Piety, C.R.; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 2)
        1 score (1 p.); 23 by 29 cm.
      - Fill Me Now --arranged for solo voice and organ, Sweney, Jno. R.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text by E.R. Stokes)
      - Fully Persuaded --arranged for solo voice and organ, Sherwin, William F.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text by J.B. Atchinson)
      - Have Thine Own Way Lord --arranged for voice and organ, Stebbins, George C.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        1 sketch (6 pp.)
      - I Need Thee Every Hour --arrangement, Lowry, Robert; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text by Annie S. Hawks)
        1 score (5 pp.); 31 cm.
        Oliver Ditson Co., 1937
      - Illinois Forever --harmonization, Piety, C.R.; 3 items (Box 6, Folder 2)
        3 scores (1 sheet); 26 cm.
        Published Prairie Pub. Co., 1933
      - It Came Upon the Midnight Clear --arranged for solo voice and organ, Willis, Richard S.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text by Edmund H. Sears)
        1 score (3 pp.); 26 by 31 cm.
      - Lead On, Master Worker --harmonization, Piety, C.R.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Margery's Carol --arranged for SA and piano, Liggett, Carr; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text by C. Liggett)
      - O Bethlehem Beloved --arranged for medium voice and accompaniment, Piety, C.R.; 9 items (Box 6, Folder 2)
        2 scores (3 pp.); 27 cm.
        Published H.W. Gray Co., 1934
        H.W. Gray Co., 1933
        H.W. Gray Co., 1934
        H.W. Gray Co., 1937
      - Oh, Teacher of the Mountain --harmonization, Piety, C.R.; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - The Old Salem Lovers --arranged for voice and accompaniment, Piety, C.R.; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 2)
        1 score (3 pp.); 27 cm.
      - Psalm 90 --harmonization, Piety, C.R.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        [Adapted by C.R. Piety?]
        (l)-Sketches (2 pp.)
      - Sewing and Reaping --arranged for voice and organ, Hitchens, Jennie D.; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text--Eccl. XI; Gal. VI)
        1 score (8 pp.); 28 cm.
        1 score (3 pp.); 35 cm.
      - A Stable, a Star and a Song --harmonization, Piety, C.R.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - There'll Be No Parting There --arranged for voice and organ, Bradbury, Wm. B.; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Text by Lewis Hartsough)
        Ink and type holograph
        Arranged or Harmonized by Parker Bailey
        Instrumental
  - Unidentified Manuscripts, Sketches, etc. by Parker Bailey, X.C
    - Unidentified Manuscripts, Sketches, etc. by Parker Bailey (Box 6, Folder 3)
      102 pages
    - Unidentified Manuscripts, Sketches, etc. by Parker Bailey (Box 6, Folder 4)
      124 pages
  - Student Documents, X.D
    - Student Documents (Box 6; 7, Folder 5-6; 1)
      13 exercise books, practice tests, assignments, notes, student compositions
  - Musical Works by Others, X.E
    Arranged alphabetically by composer, then by title.
    - The Miracle of St. Nicholas --for women's chorus and soloists, A.T.D. (arranged from old French carol); 1 item (Box 7, Folder 2)
      (Text adapted from the French by Katherine Davis)
      1 score (12 pp.)
      E.C. Schirmer Music Co.
    - Fantasy for Violin and Piano, Allanbrook, Douglas, 1921-; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 2)
      1 score (10 pp.)
    - 371 Vierstimmige Choralgesänge, Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 2)
      1 score (178 pp.)
      Breitkopf and Härtel
    - Variations for Piano on "Mary Had a Little Lamb", Ballantine, Edward, 1886-1971; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 2)
      1 score (28 pp.)
      Bruce Humphries Publishers
      See also: Personal Correspondence, General (I.A)--letter to Ballantine from Parker Bailey, 8-27-63
      Ballard, W.R.
    - Psalm 84, Ballard, W.R. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      See: Bush, Gladys Blakely
    - Streichquartett D dur, Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 2)
      1 score (48 pp.)
      Ernst Eulenberg
    - Shepherd of Eager Youth, Bush, Gladys Blakely; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 2)
      (Text by Clement of Alexandria, 200 A.D.)
      1 score (1 p.)
      (With Psalm 84 by W.R. Ballard--text by Rollin Pease)
    - A Red, Red Rose --for SATB with string quartet, Buuck, Paul; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 2)
      1 score (11 pp.)
      C.C. Birchard
    - Romance --for violin and piano, Carroll, William B.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (2 pp.)
      Music Magazine
      1 part (2 p.)
    - Hello, Buddy O' Mine --for voice and acc., David; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 3)
      2 scores (5 pp.)
      House of Standiford
    - A Song, a Smile and a Tear --for voice and acc., David; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - L'eau, Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (1 sheet)
      1 unfinished pencil copy
    - Variations for Pianoforte on a Theme by Alban Berg, Finney, Ross Lee, 1906-1997; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      score (6 pp.)
      Copy of ink holograph with inscription from
      John Kirkpatrick
      See also: Personal Correspondence, General (I.A)--11-5-74 and 11-13-74 letters from J. Kirkpatrick and letter from Parker Bailey to H. and E.
    - Douce Mémoirs (Mass), Lasso, Orlando di, 1532-1594; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Excerpts (1 sheet)
      Ink copy
    - Paolo Singing --for voice and acc., Liggett, Carr; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Il pleure dans mon coeur --for voice and acc., Liggett, Carr; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      See also: Personal Correspondence, General (I.A)--10-28-43 letter from Liggett
    - Dreams, McAmis, Hugh; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (4 pp.)
      H.W. Gray Co., 1929
    - Fair Ohio --for mixed voices and male voices, Metcalf, Clarence S.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Thomas J. McDowell, 1929
    - Israel Mourns her Lost Splendor --for mixed voices, Metcalf, Clarence S.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (8 pp.)
      J.R. Fischer and Bro.; with inscription; 1929
    - What is Man? --for solo voice and organ, Miller, Russell King; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      H.W. Gray Co.; with inscription to H. Parker from author; 1910
    - Domine salvum fac Praesidem nostrum --for male voices and orchestra, Paine, John Knowles, 1839-1906; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (15 pp.)
      Harvard University Press, 1915
    - May Night --for piano, Palmgren, Selim, 1878-1951; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (5 pp.)
      Boston Music Co., 1916; with inscription from Helen Hope Holmes
    - A Christmas Song, Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      See: Arrangements by Parker Bailey (B.2)
    - The Despairing Lover --for TTBB, Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Galaxy Music Co., 1941
    - Fairyland --opera in 3 acts, Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 libretto (36 pp.)
      Schirmer, 1914
    - The First Christmas --for four female voices and acc., Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      2 scores (11 pp.)
    - The Pearl --for solo voice and piano, Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Galaxy Music Corporation, 1939
    - The Red Cross Spirit Speaks --for voice and acc., Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - The South Wind --for high voice and piano, Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (7 pp.)
    - There's a Star in the Sky! --for voice and piano, Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (3 pp.)
      Galaxy Music Corporation, 1941
      See also: Arrangements by Parker Bailey (X.B)--A Christmas Story
    - Valse Gracile --for piano, Parker, Horatio; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      John Church Company, 1899
    - Sonata in e minor for violin and piano, Porter, Quincy, 1897-1966; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 score (27 PP-typed_
      Photocopy of holograph; 1926
    - Fourth String Quartet, Rathaus, Karol, 1895-1954; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
      1 score (35 pp.)
      Carl Fischer, Inc. (S.A.M.), 1956
    - Prelude --for piano, Roberts, R.M.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Quartet in A Major, Roberts, R.M.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Copy of ink holograph; 1963 Mar 5
    - Song of Solomon --for tenor and piano, Roberts, R.M.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
      2 scores (9 pp.)
      Copy of holograph; 1963 Jun 27
    - [Untitled piano piece], Roberts, R.M.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Copy of ink holograph; 1962 Jul 12
    - Panis Angelicus --for orchestra, Rousseau, S.; 3 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
      1 score (14 pp.)
      1 set of orchestra parts (26 pp.)
    - A Village Dance, op. 143 --for piano, 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Pencil copy
    - Widmung --for voice and piano, Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
      G. Schirmer, 1911; with inscription
    - And His Name Shall Be Called --for SATB and accompaniment, Scott, Walter; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Sarabande de "La Bonniée Etoilée", Sebastiani, Domenica "Le Grand"; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - A Ballad of Trees and the Master --for SAATTBB, Shepherd, Arthur; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 5)
      1 score (9 pp.)
      C.C. Birchard, 1935; with inscription
    - Eclogue --for keyboard, Shepherd, Arthur; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Gigue Fantastique, Shepherd, Arthur; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Photocopy of holograph; July--Aug, 1931
    - Triptych --for high voice and string quartet, Shepherd, Arthur; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 5)
      2 sets of string parts with voice part (1st and 2nd violin 17 pp., viola 14 pp., and cello 15 pp.)
      G. Schirmer (S.P.A.M.), 1927
    - Dorian Prelude on "Dies irae" --for organ, Simonds, Bruce; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 5)
      1 score (19 pp.)
      Oxford University Press, 1930
    - Sonata for Violin and piano, op. 51, Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 6)
      1 score (63 pp.)
      Schirmer, 1924
      1 violin part
    - Suite Antique --for two violins and piano, Stoessel, Albert; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 6)
      1 score (29-pp.)
      S.P.A.M., 1924
      1 set of parts (lst Violin 11 pp., 2nd violin 9 pp.)
    - The Life Broken --for violin, voice and piano, Trimble, J.H., Mrs.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Published by Miss Miriam E. Ward, Cleveland, Ohio, 1928
    - I Made My Heart a Temple --for solo voice and acc., Vanderpool, Frederick W.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Theodore Presser Co., 1945; with inscription
    - Azrael --for solo voice and acc., Wright, Fred R.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Dream Children --for solo voice and acc., Wright, Fred R.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Garden Shadows --for solo voice and acc., Wright, Fred R.; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Musical Works by Others